If you want to track conversions,
إذا أردت بتتبع التحولات،
you need to tell Google Analytics what your goals are.
يجب أن تخبر أداة تحليلات جوجل ما هي الأهداف "goals" الخاصة بك.
You do that in the admin section of your Google Analytics account.
تقوم بذلك في قسم "الأدمن" من حساب تحليلات جوجل خاصتك.
Here, Google let's you specify your goals.
هنا، يجعلك جوجل تحدد الأهداف.
Let's walk through one example of setting up a goal.
دعونا نستعرض أحد الأمثلة على إعداد هدف.
Of course, since there are different types of goals,
بالطبع، بما أنه هنالك أنواع مختلفة للأهداف.
the set up will differ from goal to goal,
سيختلف الإعداد من هدف إلى هدف.
but this will help you to understand the underlying process.
ولكن هذا سيساعدك على فهم العملية الأساسية.
If you want to learn more about this,
إذا كنت ترغب بتعلم المزيد عن هذا،
you can do so in a link that I've added in the notes below.
يمكنك ذلك من خلال الرابط الذي أضفته في الملاحظات أدناه.
I'm going to walk through the set up of a goal for the Udacity website.
سأستعرض بالتفصيل إعداد هدف لموقع Udacity.
As you may know, Udacity runs a nanodegree for self-driving car engineering.
كما تعلمون، تدير Udacity درجة النانو لهندسة القيادة الذاتية للسيارة.
For this degree, interested students need to apply.
للحصول على هذه الدرجة، يحتاج الطلبة المهتمون إلى تقديم طلب.
It is our goal to get as many applications as possible,
هدفنا الحصول على أكبر قدر من الطلبات.
thus an application for this program is an important conversion for us.
وبهذا، تقديم طلب لهذا البرنامج تحول هام بالنسبة إلينا.
Let me show you how students might convert.
دعوني أريكم كيف يمكن للطلبة التحول.
They land on our home page, here,
يحطون على صفحتنا الرئيسية، هنا،
and they may go into exploring our nanodegree programs.
وقد يقومون باستكشاف برامج درجة النانو.
Here, they can find the self-driving car engineering nanodegree.
هنا، يمكنهم إيجاد درجة النانو في هندسة السيارة ذاتية القيادة.
Then may click on that.
يمكنهم النقر على ذلك.
And once they're here,
وبمجرد ما أن يصبحوا هنا،
they find a little bit more information and may decide to apply now.
يمكنهم أن يجدوا المزيد من المعلومات ويمكنهم اختيار تقديم الطلب الآن.
They then have to fill out the application form and hit the submit button,
ثم يمكنهم ملء استمارة الطلب وضغط زر التقديم،
which is here at the bottom.
الموجود هنا في الأسفل.
Then, they get this lovely page telling them their application was submitted.
ثم يصلون إلى هذه الصفحة الجميلة التي تقول لهم أن طلبهم قد قدم.
If I track how many people got to see this page,
إذا تتبعت عدد الأشخاص الذين يرون هذه الصفحة،
then I will know how many people converted and applied.
سأعرف حينها ما عدد الأشخاص الذين تحولوا وقدموا.
So, I can set this up as a destination goal in Google Analytics.
إذن، يمكنني إعداد هذا كهدف مقصود في تحليلات جوجل.
And my destination is this exact page. With this URL.
ومقصدي هو هذه الصفحة بالذات. بهذا الرابط.
Let's see how that process works.
دعونا نرى كيف تعمل تلك العملية.
Goals are defined at the "View" level.
الأهداف محددة في مستوى View "استعراض".
I'm here in the "All User Level" for the Udacity account.
أنا هنا عند "All User Level" لحساب Udacity.
This is a view I've set up for walk-throughs like this one.
هذا عرض أعددته لاستعراضات كهذه.
I am in the "Admin" section here where I can select "Goals".
أنا في قسم "الأدمن" هنا حيث يمكنني اختيار "الأهداف".
So let's set up a new goal.
إذن دعونا نعد "هدف جديد".
There are three big chunks in the process of setting up a goal.
هنالك ثلاثة خطوات رئيسية في عملية إعداد هدف.
There is the general goal set up,
هنالك "الإعداد العام للهدف"،
then there is the goal description and there are the goal details.
ثم هنالك "توصف الهدف"، وهنالك "تفاصيل الهدف".
In the goal set up, I have the option to select a preset template,
في "إعداد الهدف"، لدي خيار انتقاء "قالب معد مسبقاً"،
or I can use a custom setup.
أو يمكنني استخدام "الإعداد المخصص".
There happens to be a template here that exactly describes my goal, submission.
وصدف أنه يوجد قالب هنا يصف هدفي بدقة؛ "تقديم".
You see it's a template I can use for the submission of an application,
ترون أنه قالب يمكنني استخدامه لتقديم طلب،
so I'm going to select that.
لذا، سأقوم باختيار ذلك.
Then, I get to describe my goal.
ثم، علي توصيف هدفي.
I can give it a name so I will recognize later what this goal was all about.
يمكنني منحه اسمًا حتى أميز لاحقًا عم كان هذا الهدف.
Let's call this one "Submission for the carND".
دعونا نسمي هذا "تقديم درجة النانو للسيارة"
The goal gets assigned a number.
يتم تعيين رقم تلقائي للهدف.
This is my second goal,
هذا هدفي الثاني،
so this seems fine.
إذن يبدو هذا جيدًا.
Then I can choose the goal type.
ثم يمكنني اختيار "نوع" الهدف.
As we said this is a destination goal,
كما قلنا هذا هدف مقصود،
because I ultimately want to monitor
لأنني أريد في النهاية مراقبة
how many people made it to my "Application Submitted" page.
عدد الأشخاص الذين وصلوا إلى صفحة "الطلبات المقدمة".
So, destination here is correct.
إذن، المقصد هنا صحيح.
Let me go to the next step then, the "Goal details".
دعوني أذهب إلى الخطوة التالية إذن، "تفاصيل الهدف"
Since this is destination goal,
بما أن هذا هدف مقصود،
we have to tell Google Analytics what the destination is.
علينا أن نخبر تحليلات جوجل ما هو المقصد.
In our case, the destination equals the following URL.
في حالتنا، المقصد يعادل الرابط التالي.
Note how I can drop the first part the URL, here.
لاحظوا كيف يمكنني إسقاط الجزء الأول من الرابط، هنا.
Google will still recognize it.
ما تزال جوجل قادرة على التعرف عليها.
Then we can assign a value to this URL.
ثم يمكننا تعيين قيمة لهذا الرابط.
Well, hypothetically, let's say that ten percent of
حسنًا، افتراضيًا، دعونا نقول أن 10 في المئة من
the people that apply actually get started with the degree,
الأشخاص الذي يقدمون يبدؤون فعلياً بالدرجة،
and that the associated price is $800.
وأن المبلغ المحدد هو 800 دولار أمريكي.
Then, each application is worth eighty to us.
ثم، كل طلب يساوي ثمانين لنا.
Let's use that for the value.
دعونا نستخدم هذا للقيمة.
We can also describe the expected path that
يمكننا أيضًا وصف الطريق المتوقع الذي
we believe users will take to get to this goal.
نعتقد أن المستخدمين قد يتبعونه للوصول لهذا الهدف.
That's called a funnel.
يدعى هذا بالـfunnel "الخطوات التي يمر بها العميل حتى تحوله إلى عميل"
You don't have to do that,
ليس عليكم فعل ذلك،
but if you have a typical path that leads to this goal,
ولكن إذا كان لديكم طريق نموذجي يؤدي إلى هذا الهدف،
it can be interesting to tell Google Analytics what that path is.
قد يكون من المثير إخبار تحليلات جوجل ما هو ذاك المسار.
Then, Google Analytics can show you in
ثم يمكن لجوجل أن تظهر لك في
the reports where users get stuck in the path and leave.
التقارير أين يعلق المستخدمون في المسار ويغادرون.
So, let's put in the typical path that we walked through.
إذن، دعونا نضع المسار النموذجي الذي استعرضناه.
So, in order to get through the application process,
إذن، بهدف تجاوز عملية الطلب،
I'm assuming that most of my students are starting at
أفترض أن معظم طلابي يبدئون في
a nanodegree overview page. So, let's type that in.
صفحة النظرة العامة. إذن، دعونا نكتب ذلك.
This is the associated URL.
هذا هو الرابط المتصل.
And remember, I don't need that first part of the URL.
وتذكروا كيف أني لا أحتاج إلى الجزء الأول ذاك من الرابط.
Then Google asks me whether this page is required.
ثم تسألني جوجل عما إذا كانت تلك الصفحة مطلوبة.
And in this case, it's not really required to get on to the next step.
وفي هذه الحالة، ليست مطلوبة فعليًا للانتقال إلى الخطوة التالية.
So, I'm going to leave this as "No".
إذن، سأقوم بإبقاء هذا كـ"لا".
Next stop is the carND page, and its URL.
المحطة الثانية هي صفحة "درجة نانو السيارة"، والرابط الخاص بها.
And I remember this one was "drive".
وأذكر أن هذا كان "سواقة"
Then the user comes to the application page and the associated URL.
ثم يصل المستخدم لصفحة الطلب والرابط المتصل.
This one is a little bit more complex.
وهذا الأمر أعقد بقليل.
And again, we don't need the first part.
ومجددًا، نحن لا نحتاج إلى الجزء الأول.
After this page, the user reaches the goal destination,
بعد هذه الصفحة، يصل المستخدم إلى الهدف المقصود،
the applications submitted page.
صفحة تقديم الطلبات.
But that one we don't need to make part of the funnel
ولكننا لسنا بحاجة لجعل تلك جزءًا من خطوات تحول العميل
as it is already considered as the end destination.
بما أنها تعتبر للتو نهاية المقصد.
So, now my goal is set up and I can save it.
إذن، هدفي الآن تم إعداده ويمكنني حفظه.
I will then be able to track this conversion in my Google Analytics reports.
سأكون بعد ذلك قادرة على تتبع هذه التحولات في صفحة تقارير تحليلات جوجل.